Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
Great Detective Conan
Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi
Ran!
"Unknown Caller"
"Ran's cell phone?"
This date is...
"September 17th, 2010"
"Beika Center Building"
Hey, will you be okay?
It's expensive here.
I'll be fine. Don't worry.
"Beika Center Building
38th Floor Restaurant"
You profligate son.
Fool!
I'm more the neglected son of parents whose
hobby it is to go off to foreign countries.
"Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend
Mori Ran"
And? What did you want to talk about?
It's gotta be for some
incredible favor, isn't it?
"High School Student Detective
Kudo Shin'ichi"
Eh?
You made reservations at
a restaurant like this one...
That's...
because I got discounted tickets.
What I wanted to tell you was...
"For The Exclusive Use of
Authorized Personnel Only
Elevator"
"Beika Center Building
38th Floor Office Area"
I'll ask you to take care of the rest.
Eh? President, aren't you going to
the company's Founding Party?
Ah, I'm not feeling well.
"Games Company President - Tatsumi Taiji"
I'll just stop by the company
for a bit then head home.
"Games Executive President - Miki Yoshihisa
Games Managing Director - Hashimoto Kyoshi"
But you said you wanted to announce
our company's long-awaited new character.
Well, please tell everyone to do
their utmost for our company. Okay?
Still, it's awfully dark in here.
"Games Director - Ooba Satoru"
As part of the production,
I asked them to overdo diming the lights.
Ahh... I see, I see.
So long.
I'm counting on all of you.
- Thanks for your hard work.
I'm sorry.
"President's Daughter
Tatsumi Sakurako"
Do you know which restaurant
the meeting is being held in?
Ah, it's you, Miss!
The meeting place is in the back room of
our usual Italian restaurant.
The lady and I are to give the congratulatory
speech at the party in a little while...
...so could you head over there for now?
Since the party is about to start,
don't be late.
Yes.
Ooba-san!
Aren't you late?
You promised to meet here
at half past 8, didn't you?
Sorry, I got delayed.
The preparations look longer than expected.
More importantly...
...did you have that talk with
Papa about us?
Of course.
He gave us the OK right off.
Then we can be together, can't we?
Yeah.
Shouldn't my courage
be rewarded with a prize?
One of your hot kisses will do.
"Beika Center Building - 38th Floor Party Hall"
What a magnificent ceremony! Thank you very much!
Please enjoy yourselves
to your heart's content, today!
Ah, seems the party's started.
At 8:30 sharp.
Before the party...
Here, a present.
Eh? What is it?
It's a pink pearl necklace that should perfectly
match the earrings you have on right now.
Thank you!
It's only natural.
Well, let's go to the party;
everyone's waiting.
And?
What did you want to talk about?
Eh? Ah!
That's...
Let's see...
For pete's sake.
I know it must be hard to say it...
...but a man has to say these things
like a man!
That you've forgotten your wallet.
Huh?
Eh? I'm wrong?
After all, you've been sweating
and fidgeting for quite a while now...
Truth is, you're right.
It was tough telling you.
I knew it!
It couldn't be that, now could it?
Eh?
Well then...
...here's an introduction to our company's
newest character, Kumakki-chan!
"Kumakki"
Kumakki-chan is winking at you!
Because there was something
I wanted to tell you...
...that's why I intentionally
asked you to dinner...
That is...
That's to say...
Kyaa!
What was that scream just now?
Most likely someone found
a cockroach, isn't it?
Nothing to worry about.
Oi! Someone was found dead in the elevator.
So, what I wanted to say was...
Have they called the police?
It's a gun! A gun!
The President of Games
was shot through the head!
That is, well...
Don't force yourself.
Eh?
Can't be helped if
you're interested in that case.
No...
Hurry and get going, Detective-san.
Sorry.
I'll be right back!
This was a showy one, wasn't it?
Most likely done at close range, wasn't it?
And? What's the victim's ID?
Tatsumi Taiji-san, 58 years old.
He's said to be the President of
the gaming company, Games, here in this building.
He was discovered by these two.
The corpse was found when
they realized they had forgotten...
...the flowers to be used at the company's
party and were going back by this elevator.
"MPD Investigation Unit One - Sato Miwako"
"Exclusive Use Elevator"
This elevator is for
the exclusive use of Games, isn't it?
That's right.
Perhaps someone came into the building
and was hiding out on a lower floor...
His clothes are in disarray...
...so the criminal waited for the party
to clear so they could target someone rich...
Huh?
I heard from Inspector Megure about a similar
case as this one that happened here before...
Eh?
I'm very sorry.
I don't think this crime had money as its target.
Eh?!
If the criminal's goal was money
and they possessed a gun...
...they would have taken this guy out
to some lonely area.
If after killing him they intended to
search him for things of value...
...the inside of a moving elevator makes for
the worst place to do that.
Moreover...
...even if you said the criminal
was checking through his clothes...
...they wouldn't have bothered
to unbutton his shirt sleeve...
Don't you think so?
Kudo-kun?!
Ran and I are having dinner here.
Can two high school students
go on a date at a building...
...with such an expensive restaurant in it?
Well...
There's a reason why we chose here.
Papa!
Papa! Papa! Papa!
Kyaa!!
You were the last ones to see
President Tatsumi, weren't you?
The three of us came with him
to see him off at this elevator.
After that, his daughter came along...
...and after the two of us briefly went over the
congratulatory speech, we went on to the party...
Do you know around what time that was?
Let's see... That was...
Half past 8!
The party crackers had started popping...
...and because the clock hand said so,
there's no mistake about it.
"Clock hand"?
You're not wearing a wristwatch, are you?
I saw the dial on Ooba-san's watch.
When he was touching my earrings.
He touched your earrings?
He gave me a present here.
"Here, a present."
He said it was a pink pearl necklace,
the same as my earrings.
It was for the anniversary of
the two of us being together...
For such a thing to happen to Papa...
Here, some water.
Thank you.
Um... There's something strange about
what you said earlier.
Is it true you looked at his watch dial?
How rude. I did look at it.
Ah...
Because it was so dim there when she arrived,
she couldn't have seen it, right?
But the hands of my watch have a luminous paint
on them so they're visible even in the dark.
The Hall was dimmed on
the President's orders.
It was one of the details I heard
was done for the sake of the production...
In that case, this is strange.
Wait.
What on earth is so strange about it?
Because, look...
If you were touching her earrings with your
watch hand, she couldn't have seen the dial.
You're a fool.
When touching her ear from this side,
she could see it, couldn't she?
Ehh...
To her ear on your right, huh?
When she saw that, she'd know.
I could see her earring on
the ear to my right.
That's why I...
What were you doing with your right hand?
It would have been easier to touch her
with your right hand.
Well, if your right hand was occupied
with something else...
...it would have been impossible to do that.
Then what is it?
Do you mean I had a gun in my right hand?
A gun?
I didn't say a single word about that.
"What's so important that
Shin'ichi wanted to talk to me about?"
"What is it? What could it be?!"
Have you...
...gained weight recently?
Ah...
"That's possible..."
"My waist has gotten a little bad recently."
"But he wouldn't have expressly
asked me out to dinner to tell me that."
Thank you for waiting.
Ah, um...
Could you hold off on dessert
until my companion returns?
He heard a scream earlier
and went flying off to it.
But since he's a detective...
...I think he'll probably settle it quickly
and come right back.
Certainly.
Um...
What is it?
Ah, I'm sorry.
It's just that you're like...
...the legendary couple
the former sommelier told me about.
Eh? Legendary couple?
Yeah.
It was at this exact seat and table, too.
It was a story from about
20 years ago, though.
Seems the man 20 years ago
heard a scream...
...and said that after he had solved the case
and returned, he had something to tell her...
So it would be best if you
resolved yourself, as well.
Something to tell her...
To propose. A proposal.
Pro... proposal!?
Good luck.
I'm sure your boyfriend did...
Huh?
He knew about that episode from 20 years ago
and so reserved these seats expressly.
This is a nice production, isn't it?
Ah, excuse me for this.
I interjected myself only because
it was so charming.
Ah, no...
"Don't tell me..."
"Don't tell me Shin'ichi will...?"
"There's no way."
Say.
It seems like you're suspicious of Ooba-san.
Since the three of saw
Papa off at the elevator...
...it'd be impossible for Ooba-san
to commit this crime.
Because he and I spent the entire time
afterwards at the party together.
You didn't stop off anywhere?
In order to put on
the necklace he'd given me...
...I went to the restroom.
Since I also corrected my lipstick,
it took me about 2 or 3 minutes.
Because we talked the entire time across a wall,
it was the same as if we had been together.
"I'm happy that you're pleased with it."
Detective Takagi!
A gun with a silencer and an empty cartridge
were found where the building collects its trash.
What?
Is there a trash chute on this floor?
Yes.
Next to the restrooms.
I see.
Without having to separate from her,
that's where he got rid of it.
Oi, oi.
Seems you guys are out
to make me the criminal.
In that case,
please explain to me how it was...
...that I killed the President while
he was going down the elevator.
And since she and I were together
the entire time...
...even if I had taken a shot at him...
...wouldn't you find traces
of gunpowder on my cuffs?
Well then, let us have a look.
Yes, I don't mind.
You won't find it anyway.
This way.
Ooba-san...
Um... Did you two kiss?
Eh?
My mother told me this.
"A lady corrects her lipstick
after a meal or a kiss."
And so... how did he do it that time?
"How"?
He put his arm around me like this.
No, no, no! Kudo-kun!
At that time...
was your back to the elevator?
Yes, it was...
Are you two always doing things secretly?
Yes.
We had also arranged to meet
over at his place tonight, too.
Miss...
We hate to be rude, but it's time to go.
Ah, excuse me.
Just one more question...
Could it be those earrings were
a gift from Ooba-san, too?
Sorry to disappoint you.
These were an impulse buy I made
just before coming here.
They weren't a present.
It was like I thought...
The President was definitely shot by Ooba-san.
There are just two questions left...
"The President's strange behavior
in the elevator..."
"...and the traces of gunpowder."
"From his ample attitude of self-confidence
that no trace of gunpowder will turn up..."
"...he must have had some kind of trick."
Kudo-kun.
At the time of the party, Ooba-san had to
take off his suit to get into a cartoon costume.
Cartoon costume? Ooba-san?
Yes.
Tonight's party was also a meeting
to announce a new character for the company...
...so he was on-stage in that
cartoon costume the entire time.
We were all surprised when it
turned out Director Ooba was in it.
The Director worked hard
to make it popular, didn't he?
He was making it wink repeatedly.
It was popular at first, but that reversed
and became boring when that was all he did.
Excuse me.
Could you show me this cartoon costume?
This is it?
Yes.
Who was in charge of the party?
Director Ooba.
I see...
That's how it was done.
Have you found out something?
Yes, pretty much.
Assistant Inspector!
No traces of gunpowder were found
on Ooba-san's clothing.
Ah... I see.
Then I guess this case was a criminal
from outside looking for money.
Get information about any suspicious persons
coming or leaving the building during the party.
No...
That won't be necessary.
Eh?
The criminal is already in our hands...
Now, shall we go up?
Up to the stage to explain what the truth is.
Oi! What do you intend by this?
Why am I being called in again
as a suspect in the President's murder?
I told you that Ooba-san and I
were together the entire time, didn't I?
Why don't you believe me?
I don't doubt you.
I think you and Ooba-san
were together the entire time.
It was while at your side...
...that the moment of the crime occurred.
At that time...
...you had your eyes closed and your back to
the elevator to exchange a kiss with Ooba-san.
Ki... A kiss?
Like this, holding your head with
his left arm and blocking off your ears...
...he simultaneously kissed you
while pressing the elevator button...
The moment the door opened...
...your father was shot to death
using a gun with a silencer.
By Ooba-san's hand.
Even if you say he blocked off her ears
and shot him with a silenced gun...
...if a person was shot and collapsed,
wouldn't you hear at least a little of the sound?
So I think she would have heard
a faint sound.
That's why the moment when Ooba-san fired
was just before the party began.
The sound of noisy crackers going off
along with the start of the party...
...combined with him covering her ears...
"Seems the party has started."
A faint sound just before that wouldn't
have made much of an impression on her.
Those are some
interesting things you're saying.
However...
There's one big hole in your reasoning.
Since the President was going home,
why was he still in the elevator?
Don't tell me he remained in the elevator
just to be killed by me?
Exactly!
Without going down, the President
was just waiting in the elevator instead.
So he could put on the cartoon costume
you were going to bring there for him.
Ooba-san.
You probably were the one who
informed the President of it.
"Let's surprise the staff
by having you pretend to leave..."
"...and then secretly bring you
back into the Hall."
Then, the reason the victim's clothes
were in disarray was...
The President was preparing
to change into the costume.
I see.
If the elevator was just standing by...
...you wouldn't have heard the arriving
"Ching" sound either, would you?
Moreover, this elevator is for
the exclusive use of employees.
Ooba-san had calculated...
...that no one would be using it up here
until after the party...
What about the traces of gunpowder?
If I was the criminal,
that should obviously have come out.
But unfortunately from my clothes...
Ooba-san.
Weren't you winking?
The staff personnel told us about that.
That all you did while inside
that costume was wink.
And you were deliberate about it.
Your goal in winking wasn't to be popular.
It was in order for you to hide something
inside one of this costume's eyes...
...so that it wouldn't move around.
Inside this plastic bag are
4 rubber bands and a glove.
In advance, you had put
into your jacket pocket...
...a glove for your right hand
and a plastic bag for covering the gun...
...to be fastened down with the rubber bands.
Equipping it that way would be easy.
And, even if you shot the gun...
...no trace of gunpowder would get on your clothes
nor would the cartridge fall to the ground.
But, if he was putting on
and removing such things in front of her...
...wouldn't she have noticed?
Of course he could do all that in plain view.
If you would please.
When the lights were dimmed like this...
...his worries were cut in half.
And this is where he presented her
with the necklace.
Without parting from her...
...he used the trash chute next to
the restrooms to throw away the gun.
After that, your hands would have been bare.
In other words,
you intentionally stuck close to her.
This plastic bag has your fingerprints on it!
My fingerprints are on that plastic bag?
Then I'm in luck.
Because I also touched that plastic bag.
What?
Oi! That's right, isn't it?
Ah, yes.
The Director told us...
..."Since if you opened it,
this one eye won't shut..."
"...and since it may contain important parts
for the costume, just put it in as is."
Here's MY deduction.
Someone with a grudge against me...
...took the opportunity to kill the President on a
lower floor while she and I were at the restroom...
...and then hid that in the costume
in order to pin the blame on me.
I think that's far more realistic than
your nonsense fantasy talk...
...about me shooting in the middle of a kiss...
...and then putting that inside
the costume at the changing room...
...before going out to the Hall.
Now Great Detective.
Shouldn't you end your
joke reasoning already?
I'm extremely confident that for each of a hundred
of your foolish questions, I can return an answer.
Now Great Detective.
Shouldn't you end your
joke reasoning already?
I'm extremely confident that for each of a hundred
of your foolish questions, I can return an answer.
Pink pearls...
Eh?
You said that when you presented
the necklace to her, didn't you?
"This pink pearl necklace
is the same as your earrings."
How could you know that?
That she had on pink pearls?
With just look, I immediately...
These earrings...
...are ones she purchased on impulse
just before meeting you tonight.
In other words...
...that was the first time
you had seen her earrings.
In this space of near-total darkness...
...her pearls were nothing but black balls.
That is, here...
...there was no way to distinguish
that they were pink.
Yes...
But then while you and her
were exchanging a kiss...
...light came from this door
when it opened, didn't it?
Now, how do you answer this, Ooba-san?
Why did you open this door then?
Ooba-san...
Why did I open it?
There's a simple answer for that.
I had sworn to my father.
That I would surely get his revenge for him.
Your father's revenge?
My father was doing quite well
at his own gaming company.
That is until 20 years ago when Tatsumi
approached him with talk of a merger.
But in reality, it wasn't a merger,
but a takeover...
My father,
who was a Vice President in name only...
...committed suicide over
his disappointment...
But...
Papa was so kind to you...
Yeah...
He drove off the debts from
my father's death...
...and Tatsumi promoted me
to one post after another.
I planned this in order
to take over the company.
No...
It was all a game.
There's a story where the main character
borrows some power from the Devil...
...in order to gain revenge against a demon.
Still...
...it seems impossible that my father and I
would share the same ending together.
You and your father together?
My father committed suicide
and made it look like it was a murder.
20 years ago...
...he set it up to look as if
Tatsumi had killed him.
However, that was unmasked.
By a young man with a very sharp mind
like this one's tonight.
It was the retaliation for having
borrowed the Devil's power.
Here.
Something wrong?
I remember!
It was Kudo Yuusaku!
The one Inspector Megure was talking about.
That case 20 years ago was settled by
the mystery writer, Kudo Yuusaku.
"Kudo Yuusaku"?
This Kudo-kun's father?
In other words, by taking over
this revenge play from his father...
...Kudo Yuusaku and his son Shin'ichi
have now unraveled it across 2 generations.
What an ironic ending, right, Kudo-kun...?
Ala? Where is Kudo-kun?
Say, have you heard?
That incident seems to have been settled.
Eh? Really?
You should meet your boyfriend before long...
He's not my boyfriend...
Sorry... It took some time.
Yeah.
Say, Ran.
Shin'ichi?
I...
About you...
Eh?
Excuse me.
The restaurant has closed already.
Ah, I'm sorry.
We'll leave right away.
"Elevator"
Ran!
Wait!
Ran...
"Bomb Warning and Murder Request"
"The Conflict Between Three People's Testimony"
"This Drama is Fictional"